Guide to the Fred W. Voget Papers 1935-1996
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
- Photos, 1939-1989; Series VI; 2.5 linear feet
  - Dancers sitting around tree singing sacred songs during sunrise ceremony, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sunrise Ceremony. At sunrise every morning of the dance, the dancers wake just before the sun rises and they greet it as it comes up. Then they sit down and sing four sacred songs that can never be changed. These songs were given to the people by a buffalo bull. (Box-folder 23/5, Photo number 318(VI):182)
  - Dancers seated around center pole, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Sunrise Ceremony. (Box-folder 23/6, Photo number 318(VI):183)
  - Dancers seated around center pole, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Sunrise Ceremony. (Box-folder 23/7, Photo number 318(VI):184)
  - Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/8, Photo number 318(VI):185)
  - Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/9, Photo number 318(VI):186)
  - Curing at Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, August 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Doctoring day at Crow Agency sundance. This is done on the second day and the public is welcome to come and get prayed for. (Box-folder 23/10, Photo number 318(VI):187)
  - Curing at sun dance, August 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Doctoring day at Crow Agency sundance. (Box-folder 23/11, Photo number 318(VI):188)
  - Crow sun dancers dancing to and from center pole, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Dancing to the pole. (Box-folder 23/12, Photo number 318(VI):189)
  - Dancers dancing to and from center pole, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Dancing to the pole. (Box-folder 23/13, Photo number 318(VI):190)
  - Dancers dancing to and from center pole, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Dancing to the pole. (Box-folder 23/14, Photo number 318(VI):191)
  - Dancers near center pole, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Dancing to the pole. (Box-folder 23/15, Photo number 318(VI):192)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/16, Photo number 318(VI):193)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/17, Photo number 318(VI):194)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/18, Photo number 318(VI):195)
  - Man watches as John Truhujo doctors Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/19, Photo number 318(VI):196)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/20, Photo number 318(VI):197)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/21, Photo number 318(VI):198)
  - John Truhujo doctoring Charlie Horse at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/22, Photo number 318(VI):199)
  - John Truhujo doctoring, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/23, Photo number 318(VI):200)
  - John Truhujo in prayerful attitude after doctoring, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/24, Photo number 318(VI):201)
  - Man and child at center pole in sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/25, Photo number 318(VI):202)
  - John Truhujo doctoring old men, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/26, Photo number 318(VI):203)
  - Old men at center pole, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/27, Photo number 318(VI):204)
  - Truhujo, woman, and other, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/28, Photo number 318(VI):205)
  - Truhujo doctoring old men, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/29, Photo number 318(VI):206)
  - Truhujo doctoring child at Crow sun dance, 1941 (Box-folder 23/30, Photo number 318(VI):207)
  - People moving toward sun dance lodge, undated; [From Aaron Brien] I feel it is important to note that the Sundance is a public event and it is not uncommon for people to be spectating solely for the sake of watching. (Box-folder 23/31, Photo number 318(VI):208)
  - Photo focused on male clothing at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] In this picture you can see the dancers sundance necklace. This is the dancers individual medicine "power." Many dancers wear them on the "medicine day." (Box-folder 23/32, Photo number 318(VI):209)
  - Two men at center pole in sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/33, Photo number 318(VI):210)
  - Crowd at Crow sun dance, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] The reason for the big crowd at the entrance of the lodge is, this was the first sundance ever held at the agency of the reservation. (Box-folder 23/34, Photo number 318(VI):211)
  - Tom Compton, Wind River Shoshoni, strengthening dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/35, Photo number 318(VI):212)
  - Tom Compton, Wind River Shoshoni, strengthening dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Tom Compton never did run a sundance on the Crow Reservation until 1942 and more than likely it was among the Pryor people. So the date on the description cannot be right. (Box-folder 23/36, Photo number 318(VI):213)
  - Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, August 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Truhujo praying for people, Crow Agency. (Box-folder 23/37, Photo number 318(VI):214)
  - Crow sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Second Day of the Crow Agency sundance. On this day the public is welcome to come in and have the blessings of the lodge and the prayers of the sundance chief. (Box-folder 23/38, Photo number 318(VI):215)
  - Crow sun dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/39, Photo number 318(VI):216)
  - Crow sun dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/40, Photo number 318(VI):217)
  - Crow sun dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/41, Photo number 318(VI):218)
  - Crow sun dancers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Dancers being doctored. (Box-folder 23/42, Photo number 318(VI):219)
  - Crow sun dance spectators, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/43, Photo number 318(VI):220)
  - Dancers and others gathered before center pole, undated (Box-folder 23/44, Photo number 318(VI):221)
  - Pete Lefthand on hill overlooking Crow encampment near Lodge Grass, Montana, June 18-24, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Pete Left Hand overlooking sundance camp in Pryor, Montana. (Box-folder 23/45, Photo number 318(VI):222)
  - Pete Lefthand standing with Campbell Big Hail, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/46, Photo number 318(VI):223)
  - Pete Lefthand standing with Campbell Big Hail, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/47, Photo number 318(VI):224)
  - John Truhujo conferring with Crow coup strikers at sun dance, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/48, Photo number 318(VI):225)
  - Charlie Tenbear armed with coupstick for striking coup on the sun dance timbers, Crow Agency, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/49, Photo number 318(VI):226)
  - Sun dance sweat lodge, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Sundancers in shade. This is not a sweat lodge. This is just inside of the Sundance lodge and the sheets or blankets are up for shade during times of rest. (Box-folder 23/50, Photo number 318(VI):227)
  - Resting after sunrise greeting, Shoshoni drum in foreground, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/51, Photo number 318(VI):228)
  - Blurred photo of sun dance, possibly sunrise ceremony, undated (Box-folder 23/52, Photo number 318(VI):229)
  - Jack Covers-up, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Jack Covers up was a well-known Akbaaalahooniliia "One who talks load at groups" or "Camp Crier". He was from the Lodge Grass District. (Box-folder 23/53, Photo number 318(VI):230)
  - Jack Covers-up and Little Nest at sun dance, Pryor, Montana, June 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Jack Covers up (Lodge Grass) and Little Nest (Wyola), at Pryor sundance. (Box-folder 23/54, Photo number 318(VI):231)
  - Jack Covers-up (Lodge Grass) and Little Nest (Wyola) speaking with sign language (Little Nest is deaf) at sun dance, Pryor, Montana, June 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Jack Covers up (Lodge Grass) and Little Nest (Wyola), at Pryor sundance. (Box-folder 23/55, Photo number 318(VI):232)
  - Jack Covers-up and Little Nest speaking sign language, Pryor, Montana, June 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Jack Covers up (Lodge Grass) and Little Nest (Wyola), at Pryor sundance. (Box-folder 23/56, Photo number 318(VI):233)
  - Little Nest posing, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Little Nest was the owner of a very well respected Rock Medicine Bundle. Known as "Iise-shoobaa" or "Four Faces". Now owned by his grandson Marvin Stewart. (Box-folder 23/57, Photo number 318(VI):234)
  - Little Nest smoking to the sun before breakfast, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/58, Photo number 318(VI):235)
  - Little Nest smoking to the sun before breakfast, Pryor, Montana, 1941 (Box-folder 23/59, Photo number 318(VI):236)
  - Tobacco Lodge, Little Nest (L) smoking pipe, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". The Tobacco Society is a group of people whose job is to plant tobacco as a part of the revitalization of the Apsaalooke. One must be adopted into this society. (Box-folder 23/60, Photo number 318(VI):237)
  - Tobacco lodge, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Society Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". Inside view. From looking at this image it appears that the woman is being adopted into Baasshussuua "Tobacco Society". Baasshussheelaakbisuua "Tobacco Dance Adoption." (Box-folder 23/61, Photo number 318(VI):238)
  - Tobacco lodge, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Society Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". Inside view. (Box-folder 23/62, Photo number 318(VI):239)
  - Tobacco lodge, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Society Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". Inside view. (Box-folder 23/63, Photo number 318(VI):240)
  - Tobacco lodge, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Society Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". Inside view. (Box-folder 23/64, Photo number 318(VI):241)
  - Tobacco lodge, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Tobacco Society Adoption Lodge "Ashchitchee". Inside view. Second lady from left looks like Mabel Pretty on Top. (Box-folder 23/65, Photo number 318(VI):242)
  - Hand game, 1940 (Box-folder 23/66, Photo number 318(VI):243)
  - Hand game, White Arm in center turned right, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Visiting White Arm. (Box-folder 23/67, Photo number 318(VI):244)
  - Hand game, White Arm in center facing forward, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Visiting White Arm. (Box-folder 23/68, Photo number 318(VI):245)
  - Hand game, White Arm in center, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] White Arm and Blake Whiteman to his right. Blake Whiteman was sometimes called Blake Packs the Hat. (Box-folder 23/69, Photo number 318(VI):246)
  - White Arm, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] White Arm, Lodge Grass, Montana. Lodge Grass named a park after him. "White Arm Park" (Box-folder 23/70, Photo number 318(VI):247)
  - Hand game, White Arm in center, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] White Arm playing hand game. (Box-folder 23/71, Photo number 318(VI):248)
  - Hand game, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] White Arm and Jack Covers up to his far left. (Box-folder 23/72, Photo number 318(VI):249)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Hand Game, Jack Covers Up. Jack Covers Up is sitting on the far left of the photo. (Box-folder 23/73, Photo number 318(VI):250)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Hand Gamers posing. (Box-folder 23/74, Photo number 318(VI):251)
  - Hand game participants, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Singers after hand game, 1941. More than likely they are singing a victory song after winning the hand game. (Box-folder 23/75, Photo number 318(VI):252)
  - Crow dancers, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Hot Dancers. (Box-folder 23/76, Photo number 318(VI):253)
  - Crow fair, dancing fraternity and hand games, Pryor, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Hot Dancers and Drum Group. (Box-folder 23/77, Photo number 318(VI):254)
  - Line of Crow dancers and small circle of men playing hand game, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Dancers waiting for the next song, with singers in foreground. (Box-folder 23/78, Photo number 318(VI):255)
  - Dancers, undated (Box-folder 23/79, Photo number 318(VI):256)
  - Honor dance and hand game, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Honor Dance following the Pryor sundance of William Big Day. (Box-folder 23/80, Photo number 318(VI):257)
  - Dancers and hand game participants, June 17-20, 1941; [From Archives] Crow sundance. Start of dance around camp prior to give away dance ending the festivities. [From Aaron Brien] Start of Honor dance around camp prior to the "Give away." Pryor, Montana. (Box-folder 24/1, Photo number 318(VI):258)
  - Eddie Roundface signals a right hand call in a hand game, Frank Hawk leaning over, Pryor, Montana, 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Eddie Round Face and Frank Hawk playing hand game. Eddie Round Face Guesses to the right and Frank Hawk is leaning over. (Box-folder 24/2, Photo number 318(VI):259)
  - Pete Lefthand with his son, Anthony, June 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Pete Left Hand with his child Anthony Left Hand. (Box-folder 24/3, Photo number 318(VI):260)
  - Unknown man, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Unknown Apsaalooke man, wearing a "Reservation Hat" which was the style during the early 1900's. (Box-folder 24/4, Photo number 318(VI):261)
  - Three unknown men mostly in traditional dress, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Three unknown men. Do not appear to be Apsaalooke. (Box-folder 24/5, Photo number 318(VI):262)
  - Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sheridan Indian Days Parade. (Box-folder 24/6, Photo number 318(VI):263)
  - Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sheridan Indian Days Parade. Looks like Donnie Deer Nose. (Box-folder 24/7, Photo number 318(VI):264)
  - Cheyenne Indians in Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Cheyenne Indians in Sheridan Indian Days Parade. Sheridan Wyoming. (Box-folder 24/8, Photo number 318(VI):265)
  - Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sheridan Indian Days Parade. (Box-folder 24/9, Photo number 318(VI):266)
  - Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sheridan Indian Days Parade. (Box-folder 24/10, Photo number 318(VI):267)
  - Sheridan, Wyoming rodeo parade, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Donnie Deer Nose, Col Tim McCoy and Supt, Robert Yellowtail. Sheridan Indian Days Parade. (Box-folder 24/11, Photo number 318(VI):268)
  - Parade float, July 1941; [From Aaron Brien] Sheridan Indian Days Parade. (Box-folder 24/12, Photo number 318(VI):269)
  - American Indian Days, Sheridan, Wyoming or Billings, Montana, 1940; [From Aaron Brien] Three Apsaalooke people on horseback near camp. The one on the far right looks like Amy or Agnes Yellow Tail. Also it appears to be at Crow Fair in Crow Agency, Montana. (Box-folder 24/13, Photo number 318(VI):270)
  - Voget's naming, St. Xavier, Montana, undated (Box-folder 24/14, Photo number 318(VI):271)
  - Katie Bear Below, undated (Box-folder 24/15, Photo number 318(VI):272)
  - Crow feast, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/16, Photo number 318(VI):273)
  - Crow feast, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/17, Photo number 318(VI):274)
  - Group enjoying outdoor meal, Lodge Grass, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/18, Photo number 318(VI):275)
  - Cars and people, Lodge Grass, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/19, Photo number 318(VI):276)
  - Unknown man giving away a horse, circa 1939-1940; [From Aaron Brien] There are two copies of this photograph in the folder. One is labeled 'Jack Covers-up, herald, announcing gift of horses during giveaway.' The other is labeled 'Pete Lefthand giving away a horse,' but in 2015 Fred Lefthand stated this is not an image of his father, Pete Lefthand. (Box-folder 24/20, Photo number 318(VI):277)
  - Women sporting goods for giveaway, Lodge Grass, Montana, circa 1940 (Box-folder 24/21, Photo number 318(VI):278)
  - War lodge reconstructed, circa 1939-1940; [From Aaron Brien] War lodge (Ashdaache) Reconstruction. Ashdaache "the lodge that leans." These are where warriors would stay during long extended war parties and raids. (Box-folder 24/22, Photo number 318(VI):279)
  - Post office, Pryor, Montana, circa 1940s (Box-folder 24/23, Photo number 318(VI):280)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/24, Photo number 318(VI):281)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/25, Photo number 318(VI):282)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/26, Photo number 318(VI):283)
  - Hand game, Pryor, Montana, circa 1939-1940 (Box-folder 24/27, Photo number 318(VI):284)
  - Crowd watching hand game, 1939 (Box-folder 24/28, Photo number 318(VI):285)
  - Summer shelter put up at Pryor, Montana, 1939; [From Aaron Brien] Sweat lodge. (Box-folder 24/29, Photo number 318(VI):286)
  - Crow sun dance, September 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Apsaalooke Sundancer praying at the center pole. (Box-folder 24/30, Photo number 318(VI):287)
  - Joe Hill curing, September 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Joe Hill, the conductor of the sundance, doctoring a woman. (Box-folder 24/31, Photo number 318(VI):288)
  - Jo Hill curing, September 1948 (Box-folder 24/32, Photo number 318(VI):289)
  - At Crow sun dance, September 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Joe Hill using an eagle bone whistle to "suck" the sickness out of woman. (Box-folder 24/33, Photo number 318(VI):290)
  - Shoshoni in street clothes at center pole, Washikie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/34, Photo number 318(VI):291)
  - Early stage in lodge construction, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/35, Photo number 318(VI):292)
  - Middle stage of lodge construction, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/36, Photo number 318(VI):293)
  - Constructing Shoshoni sun dance area, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Early medicine day of the sundance. Fort Washakie. On this day helpers come inside the lodge to put up what people call "stalls" and these are starting gate like door ways that each dancer stands in while dancing. Used to help keep you up during long day ahead. (Box-folder 24/37, Photo number 318(VI):294)
  - Shoshoni sun dance lodge, seated people, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/38, Photo number 318(VI):295)
  - View of sun dance lodge with drum in foreground and dancers in background, Washakie, WY, 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Sundance chief praying at the center pole. Fort Washakie, Wyoming. (Box-folder 24/39, Photo number 318(VI):296)
  - Shoshoni drum, Washakie, WY, 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Warming up the drum. Fort Washakie Wyoming. The drum is commonly made from the hide of a elk, buffalo, or even cattle. This hide absorbs moisture very well, in doing so they lose their sound. This the reason they set the drum in the sun for long periods of time, to regain the sound. (Box-folder 24/40, Photo number 318(VI):297)
  - Drum in sun dance lodge, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Down time in the lodge, with drum in foreground (Box-folder 24/41, Photo number 318(VI):298)
  - Shoshoni dancers gathered around fire after sunrise greeting, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/42, Photo number 318(VI):299)
  - Shoshoni dancers gathered around consecrated fire, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Sunrise Ceremony. Fort Washakie, Wyoming. (Box-folder 24/43, Photo number 318(VI):300)
  - Shoshoni dancers seated with blankets over shoulders, gathered around consecrated fire, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Sunrise Ceremony. Fort Washakie, Wyoming. (Box-folder 24/44, Photo number 318(VI):301)
  - Shoshoni dancers pray to sun at sunrise, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Dancing the sun up, Fort Washakie Wyoming. This is the first step in the sunrise ceremony. Dancers are seated after the sun is completely up. (Box-folder 24/45, Photo number 318(VI):302)
  - Shoshoni sun dance, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/46, Photo number 318(VI):303)
  - Shoshoni dancer at center pole, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/47, Photo number 318(VI):304)
  - Shoshoni dancer with woman and children at center pole, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Woman and children getting prayed for at center pole. Fort Washakie. (Box-folder 24/48, Photo number 318(VI):305)
  - Shoshoni dancers and others at center pole, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/49, Photo number 318(VI):306)
  - Shoshoni dancers with woman and other dancers at center pole, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/50, Photo number 318(VI):307)
  - Shoshoni leaving sun dance area, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/51, Photo number 318(VI):308)
  - Shoshoni dancers gathered, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/52, Photo number 318(VI):309)
  - Distant view of Shoshoni sun dance lodge, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/53, Photo number 318(VI):310)
  - Shoshoni dancers, Washakie, WY, August 1948; [From Aaron Brien] Dancers being doctored at Waskakie sundance. The man leaning over is more than likely using an eagle wing fan to touch the dancers and give them strength. (Box-folder 24/54, Photo number 318(VI):311)
  - Unidentified man, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/55, Photo number 318(VI):312)
  - Lynn St. Clair, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/56, Photo number 318(VI):313)
  - Tony Lajeunesse, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/57, Photo number 318(VI):314)
  - Two unidentified men, Washakie, WY, 1948 (Box-folder 24/58, Photo number 318(VI):315)
  - Al Childs, Crow, undated; [From Aaron Brien] Al Child in the mouth. (Box-folder 24/59, Photo number 318(VI):316)
  - Paternal clansmen praying for dancers at end of sun dance, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1975; [From Aaron Brien] Clan Fathers and Mothers praying for dancers at the end of the dance. (Box-folder 24/60, Photo number 318(VI):317)
  - James Bear Below (r) and Ira Lefthand (l) at snack bar at sun dance, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1975 (Box-folder 24/61, Photo number 318(VI):318)
  - William Yellow Robe, Assiniboine, first recipient of Peter Lefthand Award, 1986 (Box-folder 24/62, Photo number 318(VI):319)
  - Feasting at sun dance giveaway, Melvin Lefthand, wife Gladys, and daughter, 1987 (Box-folder 24/63, Photo number 318(VI):320)
  - Sun dance giveaway, 1987 (Box-folder 24/64, Photo number 318(VI):321)
  - Hugh Little Owl, Ira and Melvin Left Hand, Clifford Whiteman, and Calvin Jefferson at giveaway following sun dance near Lodge Grass, Montana, 1987 (Box-folder 24/65, Photo number 318(VI):322)
  - Robert Yellowtail (L) and Tom Yellowtail (R) at sun dance giveaway, June 1987; [From Aaron Brien] Robert Yellow Tail (Summer) and Tom Yellow Tail (Medicine Rock Chief) at sundance Give Away. Lodge Grass. (Box-folder 24/66, Photo number 318(VI):323)
  - Heather and Fredrica Lefthand, 1987 (Box-folder 24/67, Photo number 318(VI):324)
  - Heather, Frederick, and Fredrica Lefthand, 1987 (Box-folder 24/68, Photo number 318(VI):325)
  - Fredrica at age 16, junior in high school, undated (Box-folder 24/69, Photo number 318(VI):326)
  - Fredrica Lefthand being crowned 1991-1992 Montana State University PowWow Princess (Box-folder 24/70, Photo number 318(VI):327)
  - Tshirgi cattle driven down through Frederick's place, 1986 (Box-folder 24/71, Photo number 318(VI):328)
  - Feast for clan uncle by Agnes, wife of Anthony Lefthand, 1987 (Box-folder 24/72, Photo number 318(VI):329)
  - Feast for clan uncle by Agnes, wife of Anthony Lefthand, 1987 (Box-folder 24/73, Photo number 318(VI):330)
  - Crowd at feast for clan uncle by Agnes, wife of Anthony Lefthand, 1987 (Box-folder 24/74, Photo number 318(VI):331)
  - Returning to clan uncle feast after putting out fire set by young boys with firecrackers, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1987 (Box-folder 24/75, Photo number 318(VI):332)
  - Unidentified group eating, Lodge Grass, Montana, 1987 (Box-folder 24/76, Photo number 318(VI):333)